<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - JWillikers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | JWillikers</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jordan@jwillikers.com (Jordan Williams)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>jordan@jwillikers.com (Jordan Williams)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>One-liner to Fetch the Latest Github Release</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fetch_latest_github_release/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fetch_latest_github_release/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Sometimes, it would be awfully convenient to grab the installer for the latest release of your favorite Github project directly from the command-line. And if it could incorporate awk, that would be great too.[1] Well, the following command-line is a pretty nifty template to do just that! You will need curl for this to work. Substitute in the user or organization name, the project&#8217;s name, and the desired file extension for the &lt;user&gt;, &lt;repo&gt;, and &lt;extension&gt; fields respectively.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Password-less Sudo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/passwordless_sudo/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/passwordless_sudo/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Typing a password to login is repetitive enough, isn&#8217;t it? Entering the password for Sudo on the command-line can be downright irritating. If you don&#8217;t need that extra bit of protection, why enter your password more than you have to?[1] You can forever skip entering your sudo password, and it&#8217;s super easy and cross-platform. For whatever reason, I learned and forgot about doing this sometime ago, so here&#8217;s the gist.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Easily Virtualize Ubuntu MATE on macOS with Multipass</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/easily_virtualize_ubuntu_mate_on_macos_with_multipass/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/easily_virtualize_ubuntu_mate_on_macos_with_multipass/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Always Greener on the MATE Side  While I was working on my recent post Virtualize Ubuntu Desktop on macOS with QEMU, I came across Canonical&#8217;s Multipass utility. Multipass makes it extremely simple to spin up Ubuntu instances on the fly whether your on Linux, macOS, and Windows. While your VM may not be as speedy as with QEMU, I would be remiss for not doing a quick write-up on this tool which makes it so easy to get up and running.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Virtualize Ubuntu Desktop on macOS with QEMU</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/virtualize_ubuntu_desktop_on_macos_with_qemu/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/virtualize_ubuntu_desktop_on_macos_with_qemu/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Focal Fossa nestles in on Santa Catalina Island  Recently, I discovered that the Linux hypervisor, QEMU, is available on macOS. This is particularly exciting because I have to spin-up Linux VMs on macs at my day job, and I&#8217;ve wanted to get some more hands-on experience with QEMU. QEMU runs VMs quite efficiently and provides a robust set of tools for creating, managing, and running virtual machines. Additionally, it&#8217;s open-source and not controlled by Oracle.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Update U-Boot on the PinePhone</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/update_uboot_pinephone/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/update_uboot_pinephone/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[As I big fan of GNOME, I really wanted a similar experience on the PinePhone. That&#8217;s why I opted for running Manjaro ARM's alpha for the PinePhone, which comes in a GNOME-like Phosh flavor. It&#8217;s been running from the SD card great so far, but I thought to update the internal U-Boot as I did on the Pinebook Pro.
TutorialThis tutorial provides instructions for updating the PinePhone&#8217;s bootloader from Manjaro running off of a microSD card.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Update U-Boot on the Pinebook Pro</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/update_uboot_pinebook_pro/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/update_uboot_pinebook_pro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The other day, Elementary announced elementaryOS 6 preview builds for the Pinebook Pro. I went ahead and flashed an SD card with a build image to try it out. Instead of booting to elmentaryOS on the SD card as the system should have, it booted to Manjaro. While a quick restart from Manjaro caused the system to boot from the SD card, I figured it must be time to upgrade the bootloader, U-Boot.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>External Storage on the Pinebook Pro with ZFS</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zfs_external_storage_pinebook_pro/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zfs_external_storage_pinebook_pro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Note: This tutorial is out-of-date and will be updated when I get ZFS working again on the Pinebook Pro.
 The Pinebook Pro comes with a small amount of internal disk space, only 64 GB. While this is upgradeable to 128 GB, that still isn&#8217;t enough for those with large media collections. The easiest solution is to use a microSD card. And now you&#8217;re just dying to use ZFS on that, right?]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Backup Docker Data</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/backup_docker_data/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/backup_docker_data/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Backups are super helpful, especially when you like to blow everything away fairly often. Backing up the data from a Docker container can help you quickly get things up and running again.
TutorialMy recent post detailed how to setup a UniFi Controller in a Docker container. This tutorial uses that container as an example for creating and restoring backups of data volumes.
BackupCreating backups is done by producing an archive of the important files on the host filesystem from the container&#8217;s data volume.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Install ZFS on the Pinebook Pro</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/install_zfs_pinebook_pro/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/install_zfs_pinebook_pro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently, I obtained a 64-bit ARM, budget Linux laptop, the Pinebook Pro. It&#8217;s a wonderful, sleek little notebook, boasting great convenience and power-efficiency. I enjoy using it so much, it&#8217;s becoming my main machine, and I&#8217;d love love to put all of my music, audiobooks, pictures, and ebooks on it. The only problem being my media takes up a bit more than the 64 GiB available on the machine&#8217;s built-in eMMC.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>UniFi Controller</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unifi_controller/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unifi_controller/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[For wi-fi, I use use a UniFi AP. One slightly annoying aspect of this is the UniFi Controller. If you don&#8217;t have a smartphone or need to manage more than one device, you&#8217;ll need to set one up. I provide a brief tutorial for setting up the UniFi Controller with Docker Compose here.
TutorialAn existing Docker image makes setting up the UniFi Controller a breeze. Here&#8217;s how.
Install DockerFirst, you must install Docker on your system.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
