<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on JWillikers</title>
    <link>https://jwillikers.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on JWillikers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jwillikers.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Badhost</title>
      <link>https://jwillikers.com/posts/pf_badhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwillikers.com/posts/pf_badhost/</guid>
      <description>Blocking connections to nefarious IP addresses in your firewall is usually a good idea. On OpenBSD, the pf-badhost script updates PF to block traffic to and from such addresses. This post walks through my installation and verification of pf-badhost. Make sure to check out the well-written installation instructions, too.
   Configure Download the pf-badhost.sh script.
 ftp https://www.geoghegan.ca/scripts/pf-badhost.sh   Install the script with the appropriate permissions.
 install -g bin -m 644 -o root pf-badhost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNSSEC with Unbound</title>
      <link>https://jwillikers.com/posts/unbound_dnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwillikers.com/posts/unbound_dnssec/</guid>
      <description>Ever want to enable DNSSEC on your Unbound OpenBSD 6.6 server? Me too! Using this article as a guide, I document the process.
   Unbound Configuration Use the ftp command to download the Root Hints.
 ftp -o /var/unbound/etc/root.hints https://www.internic.net/domain/named.root   Download the trust anchor file with the unbound-anchor utility.
 unbound-anchor   Configure unbound.conf. Add the location of the root.hints file and uncomment the lines with the keys auto-trust-anchor-file and val-log-level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unbound Adblock</title>
      <link>https://jwillikers.com/posts/unbound_adblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwillikers.com/posts/unbound_adblock/</guid>
      <description>Ever want to get rid of all those annoying internet ads? Me too. I&amp;#8217;d been planning on using something like Pi-hole, but recently stumbled upon unbound-adblock, which is perfect for my OpenBSD home router. The setup is very well-documented there, but I provide my own, slightly-modified setup instructions here. Most notably, the cron-job runs at 6:30 AM, not midnight, and I refined the PF rule which redirects DNS requests to Google&amp;#8217;s DNS servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPPoE on OpenBSD</title>
      <link>https://jwillikers.com/posts/pppoe_openbsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwillikers.com/posts/pppoe_openbsd/</guid>
      <description>Some ISP&amp;#8217;s establish connections with their customers&#39; networks through PPPoE. I recently setup an OpenBSD 6.6 router which required PPPoE. This is my story.
   DNS Servers If necessary, configure your system to use your preferred DNS nameservers.
     A common way of connecting to your ISP&amp;#8217;s network is through DHCP. DHCP is capable of providing your system with DNS nameservers according to RFC 2132 and RFC 2937.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>